rafael.felix phd, computer vision researcher

about

North Terrace 5000 Adelaide Australia

rfelixmg@gmail.com rafafelix.com in:rfelixmg github: rfelixmg

> languages native portuguese english & spanish

> > fluent

mandarin – *learning*programming

Python, C/C++ pytorch tensorflow Matlab, Java numpy, sklearn, GitHub OpenCV

data mining

Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Neural Nets, SVMs, Gaussian Processes

technology

hadoop (basic), netbeans, pycharm sublime, BigQuery

interests

My research interests include deep learning combining vision and language for explainable artificial intelligence.

keywords: computer vision, vision+language, deep learning, open-set recognition, {*}-shot learning (GZSL), transfer learning, domain adaptation, adversarial learning

Generalised Zero-shot Learning with Multi-modal Embedding Spaces In

Post-Doc Researcher

publications

2019

	Felix, Rafael and Harwood B. and Sasdelli, M. and Reid, I. and Carneiro, G.	
2019	GZSL with Domain Classification in a Joint Semantic and Visual Space DICTA 2019 Felix, Rafael and Harwood B. and Sasdelli, M. and Reid, I. and Carneiro, G.	
2019	Augmentation Network for GZSL with Multi-Modal Inference In submission Felix, Rafael and Sasdelli, M. and Reid, I. and Carneiro, G.	
2018	Multi-modal Cycle-Consistent Generalized Zero-Shot Learning. ECCV github/rfelixmg/frwgan-eccv18 Felix, Rafael and Kumar, BG Vijay and Reid, Ian and Carneiro, Gustavo	
2015	Thresholding the Courtesy Amount of Brazilian Bank Checks Using a Local Methodology. PAAMS Felix, Rafael, Leandro Augusto da Silva, and Leandro Nunes de Castro	

experience

	Explanable full melal intelligence and violati Queentiff.		
2016-2019	Australian Centre for Robotic Vision Visual Learning.	PhD Researcher.	
2017-2019	The University of Adelaide P/T Lecturer on Foundations of Computer Science.	C/Lecturer.	
01–06, 2016	Instituto Eldorado, Brazil Outsourced for Motorola BR. Machine Learning for Mobile Applications.	ML-Analyst	
04–12, 2015	upLexis Machine Learning for WebCrawling.	ML-Developer.	
2013–2015	Sincronica Image Processing & Machine Learning for Document Analys	M.Sc. Researcher.	

Explainable Artificial Intelligence and Visual Question Answering.

since 12/19 Australian Institute for Machine Learning

education

2016-2019 Ph.D. in Computer Science

Deep Learning for Zero-shot Learning.

2013–2015 M.Sc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering
Majoring in Computer Engineering
Specialization in Image Processing & Machine Learning

2008-2011 B.Sc. in Information Systems
Majoring in Information Systems/Computer Science

awards and scholarships

2020 Dean's Commendation for doctoral thesis excellence 2016-2020 **Australian Research Council** PhD Scholarship 2018 **Robotic Vision Symposion 2018** Best poster award for Multi-modal Cycle-consistent Generalized Zero-Shot Learning 2017 Ingenuity 2017 - Faculty of ECMS, The University of Adelaide 3rd position Prize for The chessboard project as supervisor 2017 Thee Minutes Thesis - Faculty of ECMS, The University of Adelaide People's choice award 2013-2015 Brazilian Federal Agency for Coordination of Improvement of Higher Education Personnel M.Sc. Scholarship

projects

2017

since 2020

Visual Questions Answering for Remote Sensing data

The presence of remote sensing data is more often present in our lives, such as online maps, and satellite images. This project aims to guide machines to learn answering questions based on these large scale data sources.

Visual Learning

This project addresses important challenges in deep learning, such as: effec-

The Automatic Chess Board

This project addresses important challenges in deep learning, such as: effective transfer learning, role of probabilistic graphical models in deep learning, efficient training and inference algorithms, etc

ACRV

This project addresses the creation of a low-cost (under USD \$600), yet responsive automatic chess board. In this project the system detects and respond to the movement of the user, by using computer vision techniques rather than a computer interface.

2014-2015 Automated processing of bank check images for OCR
The project has two main contributions: the creation of a novel dataset of bank check images; and a novel method for processing bank check images.

2013-2015 **Document Classification and Quality Assessment** Sincronica The project aimed at developing a classification pipeline for scanned images

of documents, that included novel class detection.

biography

I am currently a Post-Doc Fellow at the Australian Institute for Machine Learning (AIML). Recently, I have been developing application on Generalised Zero-Shot Learning (GZSL), Explainable Artificial Intelligence and Visual Question Answering (VQA).

I completed my PhD studies at The University of Adelaide (UoA), Australia, under the supervision of Prof. Gustavo Carneiro, Dr. Michele Sasdelli, and Prof. Ian Reid, with a prestigious scholarship from Australian Research Council. Previously, I have industry experience. In my first position, I developed machine learning applications for acquiring data from online sources. Secondly, I was a data scientist at a Motorola outsource company working on machine learning for mobile platforms. I received my M.Sc. from Universidade Mackenzie, where I worked with Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from the federal agency Prof. L. de Castro, with a prestigious scholarship from t

On my free time, I enjoy tackling quick projects like programming affordable drones, and small robots.